Guide to the World War I Pamphlet Collection 1901-1944 (bulk 1914-1919)
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana-Missoula
- Rumania - Military: Chemical Warfare (in Danish), 1917; Romania. Mikrobe-kultur i Bukarest: opdagelser i det tyske gesandtskab. Fra officielle rumænske dokumenter. London: Eyre and Spottiswoode, 1917. (Box-folder 30/11)
- Russia - Atrocities Alleged: Against Germany (in English and French), 1910; Krivtsov, Alexis. Extraordinary Commission of Inquiry Appointed by Order of His Majesty the Emperor of Russia. n.p, 1910.; Krivtsov, Alexis. La Commission Extraordinarie d'Enquete instituee par l'ordre de Sa Majeste l'Empereur de Russie. n.p, 1910. (Box-folder 30/12)
- Russia - Atrocities Alleged: Against Poland (in English), 1919; Hladick, Victor P. The Brutal Polish Persecutions in Lemkowskaya Russia. Paris: 1919. (a map accompanies this pamphlet) (Box-folder 30/13)
- Russia - Atrocities Committed: Against the Jews (in French), 1919 and undated; Anatole, Paul Appell...Viollet. Appel a l'Humanite. Paris: Beresniak, n.d.; Comite des Delegations Juives. Des Flots de Sang Juif Coulent en Ukraine. Paris: 1919. (letter about the massacres of Jews in the Ukraine) (Box-folder 30/14)
- Russia - Anti-Bolshevik (White) Propaganda (in English), 1917-1921 and undated; The President of the Special Commission of Investigation concerning the crimes of the Bolsheviks. Details concerning the Crimes of the Bolcheviks in the City of Ekaterinodar and its Neighbourhood. n.d. (fragile; letter); Association Unity of Russia. Who are the Murderers of the Russian Czars? New York: (2 copies); Keeling, H. V. Life Under Lenin and Trotsky. London: Waterlow Bros. & Layton, Limited,; Milukoff - The Traitor His Political Record. New York: New York Times, 1917. (2 copies); How They Torture Russia. New York City: Association Unity of Russia, 1921. (Box-folder 30/15)
- Russia - Anti-Bolshevik (White) Propaganda (in French), 1919-1920; "Union" Bureau de Presse Russe. Dans la Russie Anti-Bolcheviste: Inexactitude des informations des socialistes francais. Paris: Militaire Universelle L. Fournier, 1919. (fragile); Renaissance de l'Armée russe: (d'après les sources officielles). Constantinople: Ed. du Bureau de la presse russe, 1920. (fragile) (Box-folder 30/16)
- Russia - Bolshevik (Red) Propaganda (in English and Russian), 1915-1916 and undated; Szarski, Alexander, and Faust C. De Walsh. The Great Conspiracy. New York City: German-American Literary Defense Committee, n. d.; Thaumazo, F. The Tsar's Criminal Government. New York: F. Thaumazo, 1915.; Thaumazo, F. The Blight of Muscovite Rule. New York: The Language Printery, 1915.; List of the Members of the O-BA. Society of the Russian Friends of War. 1916. (Pamphlet written entirely in Cyrillic characters, most likely about Bolshevik allies in England) (Box-folder 30/17)
- Russia - Domestic Politics (in English and French), 1920 and undated; Inorodetz, M. The Reasons for the Disintegration of the Russian Babylone. Paris: Imprimerie des Arts et des Sports, 1920.; Bogoun, V. Les Mystifications du Comte Michel Tyszkiewicz. Paris: Imprimerie de la Bourse de Commerce, (Box-folder 30/18)
- Russia - Domestic Politics: Zemstvos (in English), 1917-1927; Turin, S. P. Revolution and New Russia. London: T. Fisher Unwin, Ltd., 1917.; The Educational Work of the Russian Zemstvos and Towns Relief Committee Abroad. Paris: Russian Zemstvos and Towns Relief Committee, 1927. (2 copies); Russian Zemstvos and Towns Relief Committee. Statement of the Case. Memorandum for Dr. Butler. Statement of the Activities of the Russian Zemstvos and Towns Relief Committee. Untitled Financial Statement. Paris: 1927. (Box-folder 30/19)
- Russia - Economics and Finance (in English), 1916-1918 and undated; Stodart, Archibald B. The Economic Development of Russia. London: Porteous, Ltd.,; The Imperial Russian Finances; Certain Important Points Which the Guaranty Trust Company Neglected to Tell Prospective Investors in Russian Securities and Enterprises. [N.p.]: international monthly, 1916.; Issaeff, Anatole R. Central War Industrial Committee of Russia. New York: s.n, 1918. (Box-folder 30/20)
- Russia - Foreign Politics (in English), 1914-1921; Soviet Union. Documents Respecting the Negotiations Preceding the War: Published by the Russian Government. Cd. (Great Britain. Parliament), 7626. London: H.M.S.O., 1914.; Russia, and Andreĭ Ivanovich Shingarev. Russia and Her Allies: Extract from the Verbatim Report of the Imperial Duma, IVth Session, 16th Sitting. London: Burrup, Mathieson & Sprague, 1917.; American-Russian Society. Russia, an American Problem. New York: The Society, 1921. (Box-folder 30/21)
- Russia - Foreign Politics (in French), 1915-1919; Germany. Mémoire relatif au traitement des consuls allemands en Russie et à la destruction de l'Ambassade d'Allemagne à Saint-Pétersbourg. 1915.; Union des grandes associations françaises contre la propagande ennemie. La situation en grande Russie. Paris: Union des grandes associations françaises, 1919. (Box-folder 30/22)
- Russia - Foreign Politics: Territory Questions (in English), 1919; I. B. Notes on the Federation of the States Formed from the Dismembered Russian Empire. Paris: Fultons, 1919. (Box-folder 30/23)
- Russia - Foreign Politics: Ukraine (in English and French), 1920-1922; Inhuman Blockade Strangling a Nation: Pestilence and Famine Threaten Existence of 45,000,000 Souls-Their Civilization Is Being Blighted-It Is the Nation of Ukraine. Washington, D.C: Friends of Ukraine, 1920.; La Libre Ukraine: Revue Politique et Litteraire. Constantinople: L. Babok & Fils, 1922. (Box-folder 30/24)
- Russia - Foreign Relations: German-Russian (in German), 1905-1919; Nikolayev, P. Die Revolution in Russland. 1905.; Fenner, Heinz. Deutschland und Russland. Eine Antwort an Professor Dr. P. Eltzbacher. Berlin: Verlag der Kulturliga, 1919. (Box-folder 30/25)
- Russia - Military (in English), 1919 and undated; Military Representative of the Russian Armies Accredited to the Allied Governments and High Commands. Russia in the War 1914-1918. Paris: Universal Printing Office, 1919. (extremely fragile); Yakhontoff, Victor A. The Russian Army and the World War. n.d. (Box-folder 30/26)
- Russia - Military (in French), 1918 and undated; Recueil de documents secrets: tirés des archives de l'ancien Ministère des Affaires Étrangères russe. Genève: Éd. de la "Nouv. Internationale", 1918.; Krivtzoff, Alexis. La Commission Extraordinaire d'Enquete instituee par l'ordre de Sa majeste l'Empereur de Russie. n.d. (examples of German treatment of Russian soldiers) (Box-folder 31/1)
- Russia - Military: Prisoners of War (POWs) (in English), 1917; Ovtchinnikoff, I.A. Russian Red Cross Society. Central Information Bureau of Prisoners of War. Laws and Regulations for Prisoners of War Interned in Russia and the Utilization of their Labor. Petrograd: Typographie de l'Etat, 1917. (Box-folder 31/2)
- Russia - Reconstruction: League of Nations (in French), 1922; Russkīĭ nat︠s︡īonalʹnyĭ komitet (France). Memorandum du Comité national russe aux membres de la Société des Nations. Paris: Imp. "Presse franco-russe", 1922. (extremely fragile) (Box-folder 31/3)
- Russia - War Relief Effort (in English), undated; Friends' War Victims' Relief Committee. The Unchanging Russia. London: Headley Bros., (Box-folder 31/4)
- Russia - War Relief Effort: Prisoners of War (POWs) (in English and French), 1917; Habert, Henri. Les Russes Martyrs. Amsterdam: 1917. (Box-folder 31/5)
- Serbia - Atrocities Alleged: Against the Central Powers (in English and French), 1915-1919; Reiss, R. A. How Austria-Hungary Waged War in Serbia: Personal Investigations of a Neutral. Paris: A. Colin, 1915.; Gross, Hans. Les mensonges sur la campagne austro-hongroise en Serbie. Vienna: 1916.; Tableau des crimes autrichiens, allemands et bulgares commis en Serbie. Annexe à la note sommaire au sujet des faits criminels qui ont amené la guerre mondiale, qui en ont accompagné le début et qui ont été commis au cours des hostilités à l'égard de la Serbie par les armées et les autorités austro-hongroises, allemandes et bulgares. Paris: impr. Yougoslavia, 1919. (extremely fragile) (Box-folder 31/6)
- Serbia - Foreign Politics (in French), 1917-1919; La controverse italo-serbe: illustrée par deux exposés contradictoires. Paris: V.U. Yovanovitch, 1917.; Societe des Etudiants Serbes-Croates-Slovenes. Les souffrances des Serbes sous le régime bulgare. Geneve: 1918.; Univerzitet u Beogradu, and Gjorgje M. Stanojevic. L'Université de Belgrade aux professeurs des universités des états alliés. Paris: M. Vermot, 1918.; Berard, Victor. Les Traites de 1915 et de 1916: Discours de M. Victor Berard a la Reunion de La Servie Victorieuse tenue au Grand Amphitheatre de la Sorbonne le 16 Janvier 1919. Paris: Lang, Blanchong & C., 1919. (Box-folder 31/7)
- Serbia - Foreign Relations: Austro-Serbian (in English), 1916-1918; A Serbian poet. Without Home or Country. London: Vacher (pr.), 1916.; Stanoyevich, Milivoy Stoyan. What Serbia Wants. Serbia: 1918. (Box-folder 31/8)
- Serbia - Military (in English and French), undated; Tchernoff, Sampson. The Serbian Warriors. (postcards with pictures of Serbian soldiers); Serbia and the Serbs. n.d. (Box-folder 31/9)
- Serbia - Reconstruction: Paris Peace Conference (in English and French), 1919; Yankovitch, Velizar S. Serbia and the Peace with Bulgaria: Economic and Financial Parallel Developpement. Paris: Imprimerie Slave, 1919.; Un Témoignage Serbe sur les Roumains de Serbie. Paris: Dubois et Bauer, 1919. (Box-folder 31/10)
- Serbia - War Relief Effort (in English), 1916; Serbian Relief Fund. For Serbia. London: Serbian Relief Fund, 1916. (Box-folder 31/11)
- South Africa - Military: Campaigns / Battles (in English), 1918; Lawson, John A. Memories of Delville Wood, South Africa's Great Battle. Capetown: T.M. Miller, 1918. (Box-folder 31/12)
- Spain - Atrocities Alleged: U-boat Sinkings (in Spanish), undated; La Guerra Submarina de Alemania. Caracas: Tip. Americana, (pamphlet about the sinking of the Lusitania) (Box-folder 31/13)
- Spain - Atrocities Reported On: Catholic Church's Response (in Italian), 1916; Santamaria, Pietro. Al Belgio; manifesto dei cattolici spagnoli. Roma: Tipografia Failli, 1916. (Box-folder 31/14)
- Spain - Catholic Church: Neutrality / Intervention Issue (in English and Spanish), 1916-1917 and undated; To Belgium. London: W. Speaight & Sons, 1916.; Batiffol, Pedro. A un católico neutral. Barcelona: [s.n.], 1917.; VII: El final de la guerra y el Catolicismo. Barcelona: (Box-folder 31/15)
- Spain - Domestic Politics: 1918 Elections (in Spanish), 1917-1918 and undated; Sidi-Guatzi-Melen. España: La neutralidad de España, un peligro para Inglaterra. Gibraltar y España. Inglaterra usurpadora. Madrid: [s.n.], 1917.; Mirando al porvenir. El Partido Reformista y la guerra. Madrid: A. de Angel Alcoy, 1918.; Elecciones de 1918. n.d. (Box-folder 31/16)
- Spain - German Propaganda (in German and Spanish), 1916-1917; Alemania devota de España. London: Universe, 1916. (caricatures of the Catholic Church, pope and cardinals); Cien Pensamientos Alemanes: Con los Nombres de sus Autores y de las Obras en que Aparecen. B.M. & S., 1917. (Box-folder 31/17)
- Sweden - Atrocities Reported On: Against Germany (in Swedish), 1917; Wilson, Herbert Wrigley. Tyskarna och folkrätten: tyska vittnesbörd om tyska våldsdåd: Bemyndigad översättning. Stockholm: H. Lundberg & G. Olzon, 1917. (Box-folder 31/18)
- Sweden - Foreign Politics (in Swedish), 1916-1917; Gula Krigsböcker III: Millionarmeernas Utrustning. Stockholm: Hjalmar Lundberg & Gosta Olzon, 1916. (pamphlet discussing England's munitions industry); Cassel, Gustav. Gula Krigsböcker X: Tysklands ekonomiska motståndskraft. Stockholm: P.A. Norstedt & Söner, 1916. (Swedish professor's discussion of Germy'san economic resilience); Hauser, Henri and Erik Karlholm. Gula Krigsböcker III: Tysk Handels-Politik. Stockholm: Hjalmar Lundberg & Gosta Olzon, 1916. (pamphlet discussing German trade politics); Kriget För Lag Och Rätt I Det Politiska Livet. Reviderat särtr. ur"The Round Table", mars 1919. Stockholm: Hjalmar Lundberg & Gosta Olzon,1916.; Karlgren, Anton. Vem ville kriget? Ett bidrag till krigsutbrottets förhistoria. Stockholm: H. Lundberg & G. Olzon, 1917.; Johnson, Douglas Wilson. Krigets Problem I: Klart besked från Amerika: brev till en tysk professor. Stockholm: Lundberg & Olzon, 1917.; Krigets Problem II: Englands finanser och preussisk militarism. Stockholm: Hjalmar Lundberg & Gösta Olzon, 1917. (Box-folder 31/19)
- Sweden - Foreign Relations: German Invasion of Denmark (in Swedish), 1917; Nilsson, Werner. Tyskland och Sönderjylland. Stockholm: Hjalmar Lundberg & Gösta Olzon, 1917. (Box-folder 31/20)
- Sweden - German Propaganda (in Swedish), 1917; Tyska omdömen om engelsk politik. Stockholm: H. Lundberg & G. Olzon, 1917.; Hundra Typiska Tyska Tidstankar: Ett urval med Hanvisningar. London: Darling & Son, Limited, 1917. (Box-folder 31/21)
- Sweden - Peace Concerns/Discussions (in Swedish), 1916; Archer, William, and James Bryce Bryce. För fred och folkrätt: Till fredsvänner i Sverige London: Eyre and Spottiswoode, 1916. (Box-folder 31/22)
- Switzerland - Domestic Politics: German-speaking Swiss Concerns (in German), 1915; Meier, H. Stimmen im Sturm aus der deutschen Schweiz: Die deutschfeindliche Bewegung in der französischen Schweiz. Zurich: Verlag der "Stimmen im Sturm" E.B., 1915. (Stimmen im Sturm was a periodical directed toward German-speaking Swiss citizens); Blocher, Eduard. Stimmen im Sturm aus der deutschen Schweiz: Die Schweiz als Versöhnerin und Vermittlerin zwischen Frankreich und Deutschland. Zurich: Verlag der "Stimmen im Sturm" E.B., 1915. (Box-folder 31/23)
- Switzerland - Economics and Finance (in French and German), 1917 and undated; l'Effort de l'Industrie Genevoise pendant la Guerre. Geneve: Office de l'Industrie Genevoise,; Wohltatigkeits-Gesellschaft der Oesterreicher und Ungarn. Versand von Liebesgaben-Paketen. Zurich: 1917. (Box-folder 31/24)
- Switzerland - Foreign Politics (in French), 1918-1920 and undated; [Wuarin, Albert]. L'affaire Burrus; des citoyens suisses sont retenus depuis un an en Allemagne malgré les protestations du Département politique fédéral. Mémoire adressé le 29 novembre 1917 au secrétaire d'état aux affaires étranères de l'empire allemand. Genève: Imprimerie Ata, 1918.; Tworkowski, Wacław. Quelques courants dans la presse suisse concernant la question polonaise. Montreux: Société de l'imprimerie et lithographie, 1920.; A Propose de la Guerre! Premier Cahier. Vendu au profit de la cruix rouge Suisse. n. d. (Box-folder 31/25)
- Switzerland - Foreign Politics (in German), 1917; Alle Sieger! Ein Vorschlag und ein Aufruf von einem Europäer. Zürich: Orell Füssli, 1917. (Box-folder 32/1)
- Switzerland - Neutrality Argument (in German), 1915; Bolliger, Adolf. Tatsachen. Das Sendschreiben der französischen Protestanten an die Protestanten der neutralen Staaten. 1915. (2 copies); Weber, Leo Josef. Gedanken eines schweizerischen neutralen über das Buch "J'accuse". Solothurn: Verlag von A. Lüthy, nachf. von Buchhandlung Jent & cie, 1915. (Box-folder 32/2)
- Switzerland - War Relief Effort: Prisoners of War (POWs) (in French), 1915-1917; International Committee of the Red Cross. Organisation et fonctionnement de l'agence internationale des prisonniers de guerre à Genève 1914 et 1915. Geneve: Au Siege du Comite International, 1915.; Une oeuvre fribourgeoise en faveur des prisonniers de guerre: La Mission Catholique Suisse. Fribourg: Fragniere Freres, Editeurs, 1917.; International Committee of the Red Cross. Organisation et fonctionnement de l'agence internationale des prisonniers de guerre à Genève 1915 et 1916. Geneve: Au Siege du Comite International, 1916.; Comité National Suisse des Unions Chrétiennes de Jeunes Gens. Le ravitaillement intellectuel et moral des internés alliés: Rapport général de la Commission romande des Internés. Genève: Impr. Sonor, 1917.; Stager, A. Direction generale des potes de Suisse: Service Postal pour les prisonniers de guerre, les internes civils et les militaires des armees de campagne, 8th edition. Berne: La Direction generale des postes de Suisse, 1916. (Box-folder 32/3)
- Switzerland - War Relief Effort: Prisoners of War (POWs) (in French), 1920; Deluz, Auguste. Œuvre universitaire suisse des étudiants prisonniers de guerre 1915-1920: Rapport général. Lausanne: Petter, Giesser & Held, 1920. (Box-folder 32/4)
- Switzerland - War Relief Effort: Prisoners of War (POWs) (in German), 1916; Eidgenössische Armee Armeestab Kommissariatsabteilung. Regulativ uber die Verwaltung der Internierung von kriegsgefangenen Kranken und Verwundeten in der Schweiz. Bern: 1916. (Box-folder 32/5)
- Switzerland - War Relief Effort: Swiss Red Cross (in French), 1915-1918; Krafft, Charles. Croix Rouge internationale: Personnel sanitaire non mobilisé. Lausanne: J. Couchoud, 1915.; Note sur l'activité du Comité suisse de secours aux Serbes, Genève, de décembre 1915 à juillet 1916. Genève: [s. n.], 1916. (2 copies); Comité suisse de secours aux Serbes, Genève: Rapport sur ses travaux en 1916. Geneve: [s. n.], 1916.; l'Oeuvre Suisse en Belgique. Zurich: Fretz Freres S.A., 1918. (Box-folder 32/6)
- Turkey - Atrocities Alleged (in French), 1919-1920; Bey, Ghalib Kémaly. L'Assassinat d'un Peuple: Suite au Martyre d'un Peuple. Rome: 1920.; Qara-Šamsī. L'Extermination des Turcs. 1919. (Box-folder 32/7)
- Turkey - Atrocities Alleged: Against Armenia (in English), 1919; Turkey. Memorandum of the Sublime Porte Communicated to American, British, French and Italian High Commissioners on the 12th February, 1919. Constantinople: Zelligh Brothers, 1919. (Box-folder 32/8)
- Turkey - Atrocities Alleged: Against Armenia (in French), 1917; Société anonyme de papeterie et d'ímprimerie. Documents sur les atrocités arméno-russes. Constantinople: Société anonyme de papeterie et d'lmprimerie, 1917. (Box-folder 32/9)
- Turkey - Atrocities Alleged: Against Armenia (in French), 1919; Turkey. Documents relatifs aux atrocités commises par les Arméniens sur la population Musulmane. Constantinople: Société Anonyme de Papeterie et d'Imprimerie, 1919. (Box-folder 32/10)
- Turkey - Atrocities Alleged: Against Armenia (in English, Arabic, French and German), undated; The Armenian. Aspirations and revolutionary movements. Album No. II. n. d. (book documenting Armenian atrocities with pictures, circulars and other documents) (Box-folder 32/11)
- Turkey - Atrocities Alleged: Against Greece (in English), 1921; Turkey: Ministry of Interior. Greek Atrocities in Turkey: First Book. Constantinople: A. Ihsan, 1921. (Box-folder 32/12)
- Turkey - Atrocities Alleged: Against Greece (in English), 1921; Turkey: Ministry of Interior. Greek Atrocities in Turkey: Second Book. Constantinople: Ahmed Ihsan, 1921. (Box-folder 32/13)
- Turkey - Economics and Finance: Trade (in English), 1920; Mears, Eliot G. Notes on Turkish Black Sea Ports from Cape Vona to the Old Russian Frontier. Unites States Department of Commerce, 1920.; Mears, Eliot G. Appendices B and C to Mears' Report on Eastern Turkish Black Sea Ports. United States Department of Commerce, 1920. (extremely fragile) (Box-folder 32/14)
- Turkey - Foreign Politics (in French), 1918-1919; Arvanitakēs, G. L. Trop tard; réponse à M. Combes sur la possibilité de conserver la Turquie. Genève: Impr. Jent, 1918.; Bello, C. G. Aperçu sur l'illégitimité du sultan turc en tant que khalife. Quelques remarques relatives aux prétendues visées turques sur Constantinople d'après les sources arabes et l'opinion des islamistes les plus célèbres. Paris: impr. de Chaix, 1919. (2 copies) (Box-folder 32/15)
- Turkey - Foreign Politics (in French), 1919; Turc-Yourdou (Lausanne). Dédié à M. Wilson, président des Etats-Unis par le Turc-Yourdou de Lausanne. L'Asie mineure et ses populations. Lausanne: impr. A. Bovard-Giddey, 1919. (2 copies); Congres National. La Turquie devant le Tribunal Mondial. Constantinople: Societe Anonyme de Papeterie et d'imprimerie, 1919. (Box-folder 33/1)
- Turkey - Foreign Politics: Territory Questions (in French and German), 1918-1919; la Societe de Defense des Droits Ottomans-Smyrne. Smyrne Turque. Smyrne: Ahmed Ihsan, 1919.; Mžik, Hans von. Was ist Orient? Wien: Gerold u. Co., 1918. (Box-folder 33/2)
- Turkey - Foreign Politics: Territory Questions (in German), undated; Karten zum Weltkriege: Der Orient. Leipzig & Vieleseld: Verlag von Velhagen & Klasing, n. d. (this item is the cover to a map located in OS 45) (Box-folder 33/3)
- Turkey - Foreign Politics: Territory Questions (in German), undated; Karten zum Weltkriege: Der Orient. Leipzig & Vieleseld: Verlag von Velhagen & Klasing, n. d. (this map accompanies the publication "Karten zum Weltkriege: Der Orient," located in Box 33, Folder 3) (Box OS 45)
- Turkey - Military (in French), 1919-1921; Rapports officiels reçus des autorités militaires ottomanes sur l'occupation de Smyrne par les troupes helléniques. Constantinople: Osmanie, 1919.; Stratigos, X. La campagne d'Asie-Mimeure: Exposé général de la troisième phase des opérations du 9/22 juillet au 10/23 septembre 1921. History, v. 583. 1921. (Box-folder 33/4)
- Turkey - Military: Navalism (in Arabic, Persian & Turkish), 1915?; Total of Casualties of the English and French Fleet in front of the Dardanelles till End of May. 1915? [This pamphlet is written in Arabic characters and three other languages based on the Arabic script: Persian, Turkish (when it was based on the Arabic script before 1929), and an unknown script.] (Box-folder 33/5)
- Turkey - War Relief Effort: Red Cross (in English), 1922; Permanent Bureau of the Turkish Congress at Lausanne. Inquiries in Anatolia. Lausanne: Permanent Bureau of the Turkish Congress, 1922. (Box-folder 33/6)
- United States - American Legion (in English), 1919-1921 and undated; The American Legion. The American Legion and Organized Labor. Indianapolis: National Americanism Commission,; American Legion. Facts About the American Legion. S.l: s.n, 1919. (2 copies); Legion Expects Big Attendance Tuesday: Convention will take up important matters. Oklahoma City: The Daily Oklahoman, 1919. (Photocopy of newspaper article); 700 May Attend Legion Meeting: Convetion to be Held at City Auditorium Instead of Church. Oklahoma City: The Daily Oklahoman, 1919. (Photocopy of newspaper article); Legion not to be Political, Head Asserts: Revision of Court Martial Code is asked by State Body. Oklahoma City: The Daily Oklahoman, 1919. (Photocopy of newspaper article); Patterson, Jr., R. C. Letter discussing the mission statement of the American Legion. The American Legion Executive Committee, 1919.; Women's Auxiliary of The American Legion. Temporary Hand Book for Use of Units. American Legion News Service, 1921.; Foch, Ferdinand. Speech of Marshal Foch of France: At Third Annual Convention, American Legion, Kansas City, Mo. Kansas City, Mo: American Legion, 1921. (Box-folder 33/7)
- United States - American Legion (in English), 1921; The American Legion. Official Program, Third National Convention, American Legion, October 31, November 1, 2, Kansas City, Missouri. [Kansas City, Mo.?]: Publicity and Printing Programs Committee, 1921. (Box-folder 33/8)